A Finding Aid to the Colette Roberts Papers and Interviews with Artists, 1918-1971, in the Archives of American Art AAA.robecoli
Archives of American Art
Colette Roberts Papers and Interviews with Artists
1918-1971
AAA.robecoli
Archives of American Art
10.2 Linear feet
The papers of New York City and Paris art historian, educator, and gallerist Colette Roberts measure 10.2 linear feet and date from 1918 to 1971. Papers include correspondence, writings, teaching records, project proposals, gallery records from Grand Central Moderns Gallery, clippings, Roberts' printed articles, press releases, exhibition catalogs, posters, photographs, and a few works of art on paper. Also found are 124 interviews with contemporary artists conducted by Roberts.
Roberts, Colette, 1910-
Provenance
The sound recordings and transcripts of interviews with artists, were donated by Colette Roberts in 1970. The remaining papers were donated by her son, Richard B. Roberts, in 1973.
Separated Material
A copy of a 1967 oral history with Adolf Gottlieb conducted by Dorothy Seckler for the Archives of American Art oral history program, which was found in Roberts' papers, has been returned to the Archives' oral history collection.
Related Material
Additional papers and recordings of Colette Roberts are held by Syracuse University Library Special Collections Research Center.
Alternative Forms Available
All of the sound recordings in this collection were digitized for research access in 2009-2010 and are available at the Archives of American Art offices. Researchers may view the original sound tape reels for the archival notations on them, but original reels are not available for playback due to fragility.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Colette Roberts was a French artist, curator, gallery director, and scholar who emigrated to the United States in 1939, settling in New York City and remaining there until her death in 1971.
Roberts was born in Paris, France in 1910. She studied art with Roger Bissière at the Académie Ranson and with Henry Focillon at the Ecole du Louvre, and she later attended the Institut d'Art et Archeologie at the Sorbonne. Roberts came to the United States in 1939, settling in New York City, and became an American citizen three years later. In her early years in the United States, Roberts lectured and wrote on art and literature, and was active in various war-relief organizations, raising money and organizing benefits for organizations such as the American Red Cross and UNICEF. She was the gallery director for the National Association of Women Artists' Argent Galleries from 1947 to 1949, secretary to the curator of Far Eastern Art at New York's Metropolitan Museum from 1950 to 1951, and art editor for "France Amérique," the French-language newspaper in New York, beginning in 1953.
Roberts became gallery director of the Grand Central Moderns Gallery (New York, NY) in 1952 and remained in that position until 1968, when the gallery closed. The gallery was opened in 1946 by Erwin S. Barrie of the Grand Central Galleries for the promotion of living American artists. Among the artists represented there were Jennett Lam and Seong Moy. During this period she was also an instructor at New York University and Queens College, teaching art history and contemporary art. In 1957, she began a course at New York University called "Meet the Artist," for which she took her classes to the studios of working artists to see and discuss their work. In the early 1960s, she began to tape record her interviews of artists for this course, a practice which continued until her death in 1971. In 1968, Roberts worked briefly as Gallery Director for the A.M. Sachs Gallery (New York, NY), and as an oral history interviewer for the Archives of American Art.
Roberts wrote extensively on contempoary art, including articles and monographs on Mark Tobey (1960, Grove Press), Louise Nevelson (1964, The Pocket Museum), and Marcel Duchamp. She was a regular contributor to Aujourd'hui and Art and Architecture magazines.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of New York City and Paris art historian, educator, and gallerist Colette Roberts measure 10.2 linear feet and date from 1918 to 1971. Papers include correspondence, writings, teaching records, project proposals, gallery records from Grand Central Moderns Gallery, clippings, Roberts' printed articles, press releases, exhibition catalogs, posters, photographs, and a few works of art on paper. Also found are 124 interviews with contemporary artists conducted by Roberts.
Significant correspondents include Sam Adler, Erwin Barrie, Hubert Damisch, George Deem, Mesdames de Harting and de Tinan, Lamar Dodd, Hélène Drude (Le Point Cardinal gallery), Arne Ekstrom, Albert M. Fine (Fluxus artist), Iqbal Geoffrey, R.G. Gilllet, Adolph Gottlieb, Cleve Gray, Leon Hartl, Jennett Lam, Alberto Cifolelli Lamb, Mike Nevelson, Norman Norotzky, Jacqueline Pavlowsky, Abe Rattner, Ad Reinhardt, H. Sandberg, Philippe Stern, Russell Twiggs, and Zuka.
Writings by Roberts include manuscripts and articles about artists, writings about her own art, personal writings, working notes from interviews and classes, reviews, and translations between English and French.
Among the personal records are Robert's files relating to teaching, charitable activities, and exhibitions. Also found are gallery records from Grand Central Moderns Gallery, including artist résumés, a card file of artworks with provenance information, exhibition catalogs and announcements, membership records, posters, publicity, and sales records.
Printed materials in the collection include clippings, Roberts' printed articles, press releases, and other exhibition catalogs and announcements. Photographs are of Roberts, artists, including Ad Reinhardt, classes, art spaces, and works of art. A small number of artworks on paper are also found, including Fluxus art stamps and a printed picture of Ray Johnson stamped "DOUGHNUT FESTIVAL."
Documentation of interviews with artists conducted by Roberts includes a card index file, a few transcripts, and the original sound recordings. Most of the recordings are interviews with artists that Roberts created during a class she taught at New York University between 1957 and 1971 called "Meet the Artist," including Mary Bauermeister, Romare Bearden, Dorothy Dehner, John Ferren, Ray Johnson, Ivan Karp, Thérèse Le Prat, Richard Lindner, Marisol, Seong Moy, Brian O'Doherty, Man Ray, Ethel Schwabacher, Hedda Sterne, Marie Helena Vieira da Silva, and many others. In preparation for magazine articles, Roberts conducted more extensive interviews with Chryssa, Marcel Duchamp, Adolph Gottlieb, and Louise Nevelson. A few of the recordings of Marcel Duchamp were not created by Roberts. In all, over 100 artists are represented in Roberts' interviews. Other recordings found include lectures and interviews conducted by people other than Roberts.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1918-1971 (Box 1, 0.5 linear feet)
Series 2: Notes and Writings, 1936-1970 (Box 1, 0.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Records, 1944-1971 (Box 1-2, 11; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 4: Grand Central Moderns Gallery Records, 1952-1970 (Box 2-3, 11; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1938-1971 (Box 3-5, 11-12; 2.0 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, 1930-1971 (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 7: Artwork, 1940-1969 (Box 5; 4 folders)
Series 8: Interviews with Artists, 1959-1971 (Box 5-10; 5.5 lienar feet)
Bauermeister, Mary, 1934-; Bearden, Romare, 1911-1988; British Broadcasting Corporation.; Chryssa, 1933-; Dehner, Dorothy, 1901-1994; Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968; Ferren, John, 1905-1970; Gottlieb, Adolph, 1903-1974; Grand Central Moderns (Gallery); Johnson, Ray, 1927-; Karp, Ivan C., 1926-2012; Le Point Cardinal (Gallery); Le Prat, Thérèse; Lindner, Richard, 1901-; Marisol, 1930-; Moy, Seong; Nevelson, Louise, 1899-1988; New York University -- Faculty; O'Doherty, Brian; Ray, Man, 1890-1976; Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967 -- Photographs; Schwabacher, Ethel, 1903-1984; Sterne, Hedda, 1910-; Vieira da Silva, Maria Helena, 1908-1992; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Art historians--New York (State)--New York; Art, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Art--Study and teaching; Articles; Artists--New York (State)--New York--Interviews; Fluxus (Group of artists); Interviews; Manuscripts; Notes; Painters--New York (State)--New York--Interviews; Painting, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Reviews (documents); Sculptors--New York (State)--New York--Interviews; Sculpture, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Sound recordings; Transcripts
- Correspondence, 1918-1971; Series 1; (Box 1; 0.5 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains mainly correspondence received by Colette Roberts. It also contains letters received by Jennett Lam, an artist represented by Roberts' gallery, and letters received by Roberts' son, Richard Roberts. Included is correspondence with academic administrators, students, gallery contacts, artists, and charitable organizations for which Roberts worked. Most is of a professional nature, but scattered correspondence with family and friends is also found. Some of the letters are in French.
  Arrangement note
  Letters are filed alphabetically by their authors, with outgoing correspondence filed under Roberts, Colette, and corporate correspondence filed by individual author's name. Therefore, letters related to ongoing business with corporate entities such as New York University, Quakers, Red Cross Committee, etc. tends to be scattered in the series.
  - A, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barrie, Erwin S., 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B, 1952-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C, 1943-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - de Harting, Madame, 1957-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Drude, Hélène (Le Point Cardinal Gallery, Paris), 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D, 1948-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - E, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fine, Albert M., 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - F, 1951-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - G, 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Haldenstein, Mrs. Herbert W. (Child Study Association of America), 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - H, 1953-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - J, 1949-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - K, 1948-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lam, Jennett, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Lauck, Rev. Anthony J. (University of Notre Dame Art Gallery), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - L, 1935-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Morot-Sir, Edouard (Ambassade de France), 1957-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - M, 1945-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - N, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - O, 1960-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - P, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Roberts, Colette, 1947-1971; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 24-28)
  - R, 1947-1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Stern, Philippe, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Sachs-Sewall, 1951-1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Shumah-Swenson, 1939-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - T-U, 1949-1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - V, 1918, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - W-Z, 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Signed first names only or unsigned, 1949-1971; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
- Notes and Writings, 1936-1970; Series 2; (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
  Colette Roberts' writings include book-length manuscripts and articles about artists, writings about her own art, personal writings, working notes from interviews and classes, reviews, and translations between English and French. Writings about artists include book manuscripts on Louise Nevelson and Mark Tobey, as well as articles, essays, notes, lectures, reviews, chronologies, and bibliographies. Reviews are mostly in French, probably written for France-Amérique, an American French-language newspaper. Writings by others include articles about artists, a questionnaire about working methods filled out by John Hultberg, a lecture by Chryssa, a play by Allan Kaprow, and a film treatment by Gianfranco Baruchello. Writings are in French and English.
  See also printed materials for published articles Roberts wrote for France-Amérique, and see Personal Records and Grand Central Moderns Gallery Records for writings related to teaching and gallery activities.
  - Notes and Writings by Colette Roberts (Box 1)
    - About Louise Nevelson, "Louise Nevelson: Sculptor", circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - About Louise Nevelson, Miscellaneous, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - About Marcel Duchamp, circa 1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - About Mark Tobey (Box 1)
      - Drafts, circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Citations, circa 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Galley Proofs, circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - About Other Artists, circa 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Artist's Statements, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "My Trip to the US Aboard the Haïs", 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Notes from Interviews, circa 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Notes from Research, circa 1957-1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Notes from University Class, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Reviews, circa 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Translations (Box 1)
      - Acoustiguide for the National Gallery of Art (Washington, D.C.), circa 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - "Claude Debussy: French Musician", by Germaine Ingelbrecht, circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - "Louise Nevelson," a Poem by Jean Arp, circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - "Towards a New Incarnation of Symbols" by George Matieu, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Notes and Writings by Others (Box 1)
    - About Jennett Lam, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Epitaph for an Avant-Garde" by John Ferren, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - John Hultberg Questionnaire, circa 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Lecture by Chryssa, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Push and Pull" by Allan Kaprow, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "The Uncertain Verification" by Gianfranco Baruchello, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Miscellaneous Poems, Reviews, and Artist Statements, circa 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Personal Records, 1944-1971; Series 3; (Box 1-2, 11; 0.7 linear feet)
  This series contains personal documents and records of Colette Roberts' work activities. Records include applications for employment and funding, résumés and references, projects and proposals, lists of slides and artwork, contact information and business cards, financial records, a date book, and flyers related to her public appearances. Records of Roberts' charity work include donor lists, draft correspondence, programs for benefits, solicitations of artwork for benefit exhibitions, pamphlets, minutes, newsletters, and other organizational business records. Records of her gallery work for the National Association of Women Artists and the A.M. Sachs gallery are mostly related to exhibitions. Teaching-related records include class rosters, employment agreements, course descriptions, student work, reports, teaching notes, and a staff handbook related to Art History lectures Roberts gave on board the transatlantic ships the Aurelia and the Neptunia.
  See Series 4: Grand Central Moderns Gallery Records for professional papers related to her work as that gallery's director.
  - Applications, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Astrological Chart, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Certificates and Identification Cards, circa 1959-1963; (Oversized item housed in OV 11) (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Charitable Activities (Box 1)
    - American Red Cross, 1948-1971; (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 64-67)
    - L'Association Nationale des Ancienne Déportées, circa 1944-1960 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Child Study Association, 1964-1971; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 69-70)
    - France Forever, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - New York Council on Narcotics Addiction, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Quaker Committee on Social Rehabilitation, 1962-1971; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1945-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Contacts, circa 1960-1970; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Date Book and Calendar, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Financial Notes and Receipts, 1957-1971; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Gallery Work (Box 2)
    - A.M. Sachs Gallery, circa 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - National Association of Women Artists and Argent Gallery, circa 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Lists of Artworks, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Lists of Slides for Lectures, circa 1957-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Business Records, circa 1951-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Projects and Proposals, 1966, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Publicity, circa 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Résumés and References, 1952-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Teaching (Box 2)
    - Course Descriptions, Notes, Staff Memoranda, circa 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - New York University, 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Shipboard Lecture Series Records, 1956-1969; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Student Papers, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - United States Foreign Agent Registration Form, circa 1943 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Will of Jennett Lam, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Oversized Certificate, (Oversized material from Box 1, folder 63) (Box 11 (OV))
- Grand Central Moderns Gallery Records, 1952-1970; Series 4; (Box 2-3, 11; 0.7 linear feet)
  This series contains records related to Roberts' work as the Gallery Director of the Grand Central Moderns Gallery, which represented and exhibited contemporary artists in New York City 1952 and 1968, when the gallery was closed. Records in this series include reference files such as curricula vitae, biographies, and résumés of artists and a card file for artworks noting loan, sale, price, exhibition, and sometimes creation date and dimensions of artworks. This series also contains exhibition catalogs and announcements, published exhibition listings, and press releases for Grand Central Moderns Exhibitions. Exhibition checklists are mainly annotated typescript lists of artworks for a few of the exhibitions of 1967 and 1968. Other business records in this series include loan agreements for both French and American artists involved in the 1953 exhibition exchange held by Grand Central Moderns Gallery and Galerie Jeanne Bucher in Paris. Also found are receipts for loans, membership lists, price quotes, and sales records. An open letter of support for the Gallery, written when it closed and signed by ten artists, is also found.
  Announcements, catalogs, and press releases for exhibitions at other galleries are found in Series 5: Printed Materials. For correspondence with artists and Grand Central Galleries Manager Erwin Barrie, see Series 1: Correspondence. See Series 4: Personal Records for records from Roberts' work with A.M. Sachs Gallery and the Argent Gallery of the National Association of Women Artists.
  - Artist Biographies and Résumés (Box 2)
    - Adler - Ray Johnson, circa 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Kortlander - Murch, circa 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Nevelson - Yunkers, circa 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Card File of Artworks (Box 2)
    - Banks - Caldwell, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Conway - Durfee, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Elliott - Lam, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Madrigal - Moy, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Niewald - Shahly, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Taplitz - Zuka, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1952-1968 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition Listings, circa 1952-1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Letter of Support, circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Loan Agreements, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Loan and Shipping Receipts, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Membership Lists, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Posters, 1960-1968; (Oversized material housed in OV 11) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Publicity, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Price Quotations for Artwork, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Receipts from Sales of Artwork, 1958-1969; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Sales Lists, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Posters, (Oversized material from Box 3, folder 5) (Box 11 (OV))
- Printed Material, 1938-1971; Series 5; (Box 3-5, 11-12; 2.0 linear feet)
  This series contains published articles by Roberts and other authors, newspaper and magazine clippings, newsletters of organizations with which Roberts was involved, pamphlets, publicity materials, exhibition announcements, catalogs, posters, and press releases. Articles by Colette Roberts are in French and English, clipped and copied from a variety of publications. Roberts' France-Amérique articles are mostly reviews of current exhibitions in New York in French. Articles by others are generally longer writings on art and literature published in journals and magazines by authors including Henry Miller, Philippe Stern, Richard Wright, Dore Ashton, and Dick Higgins, among others. Clippings include reviews of Grand Central Moderns exhibitions, and other happenings in the art world, particularly in New York City and the contemporary art scene of the 1950s and 1960s. Also found are clippings about artists of interest to Roberts such as Jennett Lam, Mark Tobey, George Mattieu, and Louise Nevelson.
  Newsletters are from the MacDowell Colony, the Peridot Gallery, the Art Students League, and places where Roberts taught. Press releases are mostly for exhibitions of contemporary artists in New York City, at both museums and galleries. Tamarind Lithograph Workshop publications include paper samples, drystamps, and biographies of printmakers. Art-related pamphlets include brochures, publicity, and mailings from cultural organizations in the arts. Non-art-related pamphlets relate to travel, financial, manuals, and other miscellany.
  For printed materials related to the Grand Central Moderns Gallery, see Series 4: Grand Central Moderns Gallery Records.
  - Articles by Colette Roberts, circa 1952-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles by Colette Roberts in France-Amérique, 1953-1959; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
  - Articles by Colette Roberts in France-Amérique, 1960-1969; (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 16-20)
  - Articles by Colette Roberts in France-Amérique, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Articles by Colette Roberts in France-Amérique, circa 1953-1971; (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 22-31)
  - Articles by Others, 1944-1969 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Catalogs for Art Slides, circa 1957-1970 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Catalogs and Ads for Books, circa 1955-1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 36-39)
  - Clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 40-48)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings about Colette Roberts, 1947-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1950-1957; (OV item housed in OV 11) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1960-1962; (OV item housed in OV 11) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1950-1971; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1938-1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)